<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:sioc="http://rdfs.org/sioc/ns#" xmlns:sioct="http://rdfs.org/sioc/types#" xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" version="2.0" xml:base="https://techtransfer.cancer.gov/rss/diagnostics/abstracts.xml">
  <channel>
    <title>Diagnostics</title>
    <link>http://www.example.com</link>
    <description>Available Technologies from the Technology Transfer Center.</description>
    <language/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.example.com" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>High-Throughput Assay for Detection and Monitoring of Endocrine Disrupting Chemicals in Water Sources</title>
      <link>http://default/bundle/nci-e-269-2011</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is growing awareness that a wide variety of synthetic and natural compounds that may be present in water sources, such as streams, wells, and ground water, may lead to adverse health effects, including increased cancer risk. Even low concentrations of these compounds are of concern, as they may have biological effects at concentrations of parts per billion or less. In particular, the presence of endocrine disrupting chemicals (EDCs) in the environment is under examination for potential adverse effects on human health, such as immune suppression, impaired fertility, and increased incidence of cancer, diabetes, and obesity. However, these compounds are often laborious and difficult to measure and thus are not commonly monitored. In addition, even if such compounds are detected, only the known compound itself is typically measured, neglecting its metabolites which are more likely to be found in water samples and retain endocrine disrupting activity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Inventors at the NCI’s Laboratory of Receptor Biology and Gene Expression have developed a novel assay methodology for detecting EDCs in contaminated water. The assay utilizes fluorescently labeled nuclear steroid receptor constructs in a high-throughput, mammalian cell-based format. Detection and measurements are based on translocation of the fluorescent marker from the cytoplasm to the nucleus in the presence of a ligand that interacts with a specific steroid receptor. Overall, this assay has the capability to detect very low concentrations of EDCs in water or other liquid samples. The inventors have demonstrated proof of concept for this technology by testing for the presence of Glucocorticoid Receptor (GR), Androgen Receptor (AR), Estrogen Receptor (ER), Aryl hydrocarbon receptor (AhR), Progesterone Receptor (PR), and Thyroid Hormone Receptor (TR) activity in water samples. For example, NCI scientists screened water samples collected from 14 states in the US and found AR activity in 35% of samples, as well as previously unrecognized glucocorticoid (GC) activity in 27% of the samples. In particular, the compound androst-4-en-3,6-dione was identified in one of the samples. AR-dependent nuclear translocation and transcriptional activation was also confirmed for two AR-responsive genes, NKX3.1 and RHOU. Moreover, NKX3.1 is a homeobox gene frequently deleted in prostate cancers, and RHOU is implicated in epidermal growth factor receptor signaling and cell migration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A product or service based on this technology could fulfill an unmet need for a high-throughput, rapid method for screening multiple water samples for contaminants with potential endocrine-disrupting activity. The NCI is seeking co-development partners and/or licensees for this technology as a product or service for detecting and screening for endocrine disrupting chemicals in water samples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/NCI-E-269-2011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Method for HLA LOH Detection in Liquid Biopsies</title>
      <link>http://default/bundle/nci-e-045-2022</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Human leukocyte antigen (HLA) LOH (LOH) is a known resistance mechanism by which cancers evade T cell receptor-(TCR-)based immunotherapies. This class of therapies includes immune checkpoint inhibition (ICI, e.g., Pembrolizumab), engineered TCR (T cell receptor)-T cell adoptive transfer, tumor infiltrating lymphocytes (TIL), T-cell engagers, and other modalities. Dozens of therapies in this category were developed with many in clinical trials. The resistance mechanism noted here, HLA LOH, causes these therapies to fail. Therefore, it is beneficial to know before treating a patient whether their cancer’s genome has undergone HLA LOH. There is currently no HLA LOH detection method with widespread use in the market and, furthermore, no non-invasive HLA LOH detection test available. Approximately 17% of all cancer patients undergo HLA LOH (Montesion et al., Cancer Discovery, 2021) and would therefore be less likely to respond to TCR-based immunotherapies, making a test for HLA LOH crucial for attaining better patient outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inventors at the National Cancer Institute (NCI) a developed a non-invasive test for HLA LOH detection in liquid biopsies from blood. As a companion diagnostic (CDx), this HLA LOH detection method allows for improved patient selection. It determines patients unlikely to benefit prior to immunotherapy and thus, can avoid the toxicity, costs, and prevent delay in effective therapy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an application of precision oncology. For HLA LOH detection, treatment decisions can be based in part on the HLA LOH status of the patient’s cancer, and a patient’s treatment course is tailored to give the patient rapid access to more effective therapy. Because the test is non-invasive, determining HLA LOH status does not require surgery. This dramatically increases patient comfort, improves their experience and decreases healthcare costs. An additional benefit is that the patient will not undergo unnecessary treatments that could cause toxicities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Center for Immuno-Oncology at the NCI is primarily looking for collaborators to co-develop this technology with the inventor. As a companion diagnostic, it will be paired with immunotherapies, to select patients who are most likely to achieve treatment benefit. The inventors seek co-development partners who developed immunotherapies that function via TCR-based mechanisms. The goal is to conduct clinical trials for the diagnostic concomitantly with the drug. The end-result of the trial will be determination of how accurately the diagnostic predicts efficacy of the drug. A companion diagnostic can increase the market potential of therapeutics by allowing them to be used as a first-line treatment. The companion diagnostic can be co-developed and/or co-marketed with a drug at any stage of the drug’s regulatory approval process, from Phase I to FDA-approved. The next step for the diagnostic is a Phase I clinical trial, with possible IDE exemption. The companion diagnostic may also be a candidate for College of American Pathologists (CAP) accreditation and, more stringently, Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendments (CLIA) designation while the clinical trials are being conducted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/NCI-E-045-2022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Method for HLA LOH Detection in Liquid Biopsies</title>
      <link>http://default/bundle/nci-045-2022</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Human leukocyte antigen (HLA) LOH (LOH) is a known resistance mechanism by which cancers evade T cell receptor-(TCR-)based immunotherapies. This class of therapies includes immune checkpoint inhibition (ICI, e.g., Pembrolizumab), engineered TCR (T cell receptor)-T cell adoptive transfer, tumor infiltrating lymphocytes (TIL), T-cell engagers, and other modalities. Dozens of therapies in this category were developed with many in clinical trials. The resistance mechanism noted here, HLA LOH, causes these therapies to fail. Therefore, it is beneficial to know before treating a patient whether their cancer’s genome has undergone HLA LOH. There is currently no HLA LOH detection method with widespread use in the market and, furthermore, no non-invasive HLA LOH detection test available. Approximately 17% of all cancer patients undergo HLA LOH (Montesion et al., Cancer Discovery, 2021) and would therefore be less likely to respond to TCR-based immunotherapies, making a test for HLA LOH crucial for attaining better patient outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inventors at the National Cancer Institute (NCI) a developed a non-invasive test for HLA LOH detection in liquid biopsies from blood. As a companion diagnostic (CDx), this HLA LOH detection method allows for improved patient selection. It determines patients unlikely to benefit prior to immunotherapy and thus, can avoid the toxicity, costs, and prevent delay in effective therapy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an application of precision oncology. For HLA LOH detection, treatment decisions can be based in part on the HLA LOH status of the patient’s cancer, and a patient’s treatment course is tailored to give the patient rapid access to more effective therapy. Because the test is non-invasive, determining HLA LOH status does not require surgery. This dramatically increases patient comfort, improves their experience and decreases healthcare costs. An additional benefit is that the patient will not undergo unnecessary treatments that could cause toxicities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Center for Immuno-Oncology at the NCI is primarily looking for collaborators to co-develop this technology with the inventor. As a companion diagnostic, it will be paired with immunotherapies, to select patients who are most likely to achieve treatment benefit. The inventors seek co-development partners who developed immunotherapies that function via TCR-based mechanisms. The goal is to conduct clinical trials for the diagnostic concomitantly with the drug. The end-result of the trial will be determination of how accurately the diagnostic predicts efficacy of the drug. A companion diagnostic can increase the market potential of therapeutics by allowing them to be used as a first-line treatment. The companion diagnostic can be co-developed and/or co-marketed with a drug at any stage of the drug’s regulatory approval process, from Phase I to FDA-approved. The next step for the diagnostic is a Phase I clinical trial, with possible IDE exemption. The companion diagnostic may also be a candidate for College of American Pathologists (CAP) accreditation and, more stringently, Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendments (CLIA) designation while the clinical trials are being conducted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/NCI-045-2022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monoclonal Antibodies for the Recognition of Oncogene Fusions and Alveolar Rhabdomyosarcoma (ARMS) Diagnosis</title>
      <link>http://default/tech/tab-3639</link>
      <description>This technology includes monoclonal antibody (mAb) that binds to the junction region of the PAX3-FOXO1 and PAX7-FOXO1 fusion protein for the diagnosis of Alveolar Rhabdomyosarcoma (ARMS). Specifically, two monoclonal antibodies (PFM.1 and PFM.2) have been isolated that recognize the 92kDa bands found uniquely to the pediatric striated muscle tumors of the type Alveolar Rhabdomyosarcoma (ARMS) carrying the characteristic t(2;13)(q35;q14) or t(1;13)(p36;q14) chromosomal translocations. This in-frame fusion protein is unique to the most common type of ARMS and acts as a potent transcriptional activator as the result of a decreased regulatory (of PAX3/7) sensitivity of the C-terminal domain of FOXO1. The mAbs recognize the ARMS fusion protein PAX3/7 FKHR on western analysis and do not recognize PAX3/7 or FOXO1 alone. The antibodies work by Westerns, Co-Immunoprecipitation, Chromatin Immunoprecipitation Sequencing (CHipSeq), and immunohistochemistry.</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/TAB-3639</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SARS-CoV-2 Neutralizing Antibodies and Synthetic Nanobody Library Using a Humanized Llama Framework Region</title>
      <link>http://default/tech/tab-3640</link>
      <description>NCATS has developed a highly diverse synthetic library that will allow for the rapid identification of novel nanobodies that bind to a wide arrange of target antigens. The humanized framework used to construct the library will facilitate the transition of lead candidates into patient studies. Several highly potent SARS-CoV-2 nanobodies (antibodies) have been identified and are available for further development.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
NCATS is actively seeking licensing for the 1) a synthetic library and 2) the potent neutralizing antibodies with activity against SARS-CoV-2.</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/TAB-3640</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time Efficient Multi-Pulsed Field Gradient (mPFG) MRI Without Concomitant Gradient Field Artifacts</title>
      <link>http://default/bundle/nci-e-170-2020</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Measuring and mapping nervous tissue microstructure noninvasively is a long sought-after goal in neuroscience. Clinically, several neuropathologies such as cancer and stroke, are associated with changes in tissue microstructure. Diffusion tensor imaging (DTI), which models diffusion anisotropy, is an ideal imaging modality to elucidate these changes. However, DTI provides a mean diffusion tensor averaged over the entire MRI voxel. This has limitations when applied to heterogeneous neural tissue. Although some of these could be overcome by increased spatial resolution, this comes at the cost of reduced signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) and increased scan time. The SNR limitation makes it impractical to resolve individual neuronal soma and axons whose size range between 0.1-60 µm. Multiple pulsed field gradient (mPFG) methods can resolve microscopic features several orders of magnitude smaller than the typical MRI voxel size – for example, plant cell size and pore diameters in phantoms – using lower gradient strengths compared to single PFG methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This technology describes methods and apparatus to measure and map the diffusion tensor distribution (DTD) in neural tissue or other specimens. Efficient and translatable methods of performing mPFG MRI experiments in a single spin echo sequence to generate b-matrices of ranks one, two, or three, without concomitant gradient field artifacts are disclosed. The disclosed approaches and signal inversion framework captures features of heterogeneity and anisotropy in the spinal cord or other specimens. The disclosed stains may have utility in assessing disease (e.g., cancer), normal and abnormal developmental processes, degeneration and trauma in the brain and other soft tissues, and other applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development (NICHD) seeks research co-development partners and/or licensees for the development of diffusion tensor distribution MR imaging (DTD-MRI) in assessing disease (e.g., cancer), normal and abnormal developmental processes, degeneration and trauma in the brain and other soft tissues, or in other applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/NCI-E-170-2020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic Lethality-mediated Precision Oncology via the Tumor Transcriptome</title>
      <link>http://default/bundle/nci-e-150-2020</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The use of tumor transcriptomics for precision oncology has made significant advances, mainly by identifying cancer driver genes or actionable mutations for treatment with targeted therapies.  However, this strategy misses out on broader genetic interactions that could reveal additional biologically testable biomarkers for therapy response prediction and inform the selection of more effective drugs for targeted treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists at the National Cancer Institute (NCI) have developed SELECT, a computational, precision-oncology framework that uses the tumor’s whole transcriptome to identify synthetic lethal and synthetic rescue genetic interactions.  These genetic interactions provided actional information predicting therapeutic response in 28 of 35 published targeted and immunotherapy trials from 10 different cancer types. Also, it was predictive of patients’ response in 80 % of these clinical trials.  SELECT, an excellent tool in developing new targeted therapies or enhancing patient stratification in transcriptomic multi-arm trials, is available for co-development or licensing opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/NCI-E-150-2020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Viral Exposure Signature to Define and Detect Early Onset Hepatocellular Carcinoma</title>
      <link>http://default/bundle/nci-e-174-2019</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Early detection of liver cancer, such as hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC), is key to improve cancer-related mortality. More than 800,000 people are diagnosed with this cancer each year throughout the world. Liver cancer is also a leading cause of cancer deaths worldwide, accounting for more than 700,000 deaths each year. Currently, millions of Americans and possibly billions in the world are considered at risk for developing liver cancer. Individuals are considered at risk for developing liver cancer if they have underlying chronic liver diseases such as fibrosis and cirrhosis which in turn may be caused by viral infections and inflammation. However, this risk greatly varies among individuals and the current methods for early detection and surveillance are inadequate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists at the National Cancer Institute’s (NCI) Laboratory of Human Carcinogenesis established a biomarker signature of viral infection that can predict HCC among at-risk individuals up to 7 years prior to their clinical diagnosis. This viral exposure signature has been identified through serological profiling of individuals from a case-control study and validated in a cohort of at-risk individuals who were followed up to 20 years for the development of HCC. The specificity and sensitivity of this biomarker signature is superior to current available methods of diagnosis such as alpha-fetoprotein screening. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NCI seeks proposals from parties interested in co-development and licensing opportunities to employ this viral exposure signature in diagnostic assays of early onset HCC.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/NCI-E-174-2019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Classification of Primary Mediastinal Large B Cell Lymphoma Using Formalin-Fixed, Paraffin-Embedded Tissue Specimens</title>
      <link>http://default/bundle/nci-e-172-2017</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Primary mediastinal B-cell lymphoma (PMBCL) is an aggressive type of non-Hodgkin lymphoma that mostly occurs in people between the ages of 30-40. It accounts for 5-7% of all aggressive lymphomas. The diagnosis of PMBCL is challenging as the histological features of PMBCL overlap with diffuse large B-cell lymphoma (DLBCL), another most common type of non-Hodgkin lymphoma. Available evidence suggests that PMBCL responds much more favorably to the DA-EPOCH-R chemotherapy regimen than to the standard R-CHOP regimen used to treat DLBCL. The diagnostic uncertainty of PMBCL can result in delayed and/or inappropriate treatment, serious harm, and even death of the patient, so there is a need to more precisely diagnose PMBCL.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the National Cancer Institute (NCI) have developed a gene expression-based assay comprising a set of 58 nucleic acid probes that measure the abundance of selected mRNA species using the Nanostring platform. This assay can be used successfully to better distinguish PMBCL from DLBCL and applied to further classify DLBCL into well-established cell-of-origin subtypes. This test can be applied by clinicians to support the pathological diagnosis of PMBCL, and therefore identify a group of patients whose tumors are characterized by a distinct underlying biology.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NCI seeks licensees and/or co-development partners to develop this technology toward commercialization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/NCI-E-172-2017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diagnostic Assay for Determining Patient Response to Apoptosis-related Cancer Therapy</title>
      <link>http://default/bundle/nci-e-195-2018</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many known chemotherapeutic drugs kill abnormal cells through a process called apoptosis. Bcl-2 proteins are negative regulators of apoptosis that control cell survival and death. Increased expression of anti-apoptotic Bcl-2 proteins commonly occurs in up to 30% of all cancers, providing cancer cells a pro-survival advantage to evade cell death, grow, and proliferate. Drugs targeting these specific anti-apoptotic proteins are potential anti-cancer therapeutics. A need exists for improved methods to select patients that may benefit from drugs targeting apoptotic pathway, such as Bcl-2 homology domain-3 (BH3) mimetics. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the NCI developed a multiplex assay to determine the efficacy of apoptosis-related drugs targeting the Bcl2 family of proteins or aid in the selection of cancer patients likely to respond. The immunoassay quantitatively measures heterodimer protein complexes of specific Bcl-2 family proteins. Traditional assays performed in needle biopsies only measure individual Bcl-2 family proteins and do not capture the protein-protein interactions.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assay was confirmed using tumor tissue biopsy samples and has the potential to predict drug efficacy. The assay may be useful as a companion diagnostic in conjunction with apoptosis-inducing agents.  The assay also has the potential to aid in the selection of cancer patients likely to respond to drugs targeting the apoptosis pathway.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/NCI-E-195-2018</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
