<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:sioc="http://rdfs.org/sioc/ns#" xmlns:sioct="http://rdfs.org/sioc/types#" xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" version="2.0" xml:base="https://techtransfer.cancer.gov/rss/diagnostics/abstracts.xml">
  <channel>
    <title>Medical Devices</title>
    <link>http://www.example.com</link>
    <description>Available Technologies from the Technology Transfer Center.</description>
    <language/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.example.com" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Automatic System and Method for Tissue Sectioning, Staining, and Scanning</title>
      <link>http://default/bundle/nci-e-003-2022</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Computer and imaging technologies led to the development of digital pathology and the capture and storage of pathological specimens as digitally formatted images. The use of artificial intelligence (AI) in digital pathology, such as in three-dimensional (3D) reconstruction, requires analyses of high volumes of data. This results in increased demands for processing and acquisition of digital images of pathology samples. Increased usage cannot be met by the time-consuming, manual, and laborious methods currently used. Therefore, there is a need for automation of techniques used in processing of pathology samples and acquisition of digital images to make them amenable with high-throughput approaches such as AI analysis.&lt;br /&gt;
	National Cancer Institute inventors developed an automated device with integrated tissue sectioning, staining, scanning, and high-throughput capability. This device integrates pathology sample processing (e.g., sectioning, fixing, and staining) with optical scanning and digital image acquisition. This invention, related to another technology, E-084-2019, is updated to include a coated tape for holding and carrying sample sections as an alternative to a carrier film. The tape carries sequentially cut sample slices into a staining cassette where the slices are simultaneously stained directly on the tape. The tape carrying the stained samples are then fed into the imaging unit. This streamlines the entire process enabling high-throughput preparation of large volumes of samples and data for subsequent AI analysis. As a result of automation, the device saves time, minimizes errors, and reduces wasting reagents and supplies. Automation is expected to reduce sample processing time ten-fold.&lt;br /&gt;
	The NCI is seeking licensees to develop an automated digital pathology device compatible with high-throughput data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/NCI-E-003-2022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated Digital Pathology Device for High-Throughput Demand</title>
      <link>http://default/bundle/nci-e-084-2019</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Computer and imaging technologies led to the development of digital pathology and the capture and storage of pathological specimens as digitally formatted images. The use of artificial intelligence (AI) in digital pathology, such as in three-dimensional (3D) reconstruction, requires analyses of high volumes of data. This resulted in increased demands for processing and acquisition of digital images of pathology samples. Increased usage cannot be met by the time-consuming, manual, and laborious methods currently used. Therefore, there is a need for automation of the techniques used in processing of pathology samples and acquisition of digital images to make them amenable with high-throughput approaches like AI analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National Cancer Institute inventors are developing an automated device with integrated tissue sectioning, staining, scanning, and high-throughput capability. This device integrates pathology sample processing (e.g., sectioning, fixing, and staining) with optical scanning and digital image acquisition. This streamlines the entire process enabling high-throughput preparation of large volumes of samples and data for subsequent AI analysis. As a result of automation, the device saves time, minimizes errors, and reduces wasting reagents and supplies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NCI is seeking licensees to develop an automated digital pathology device compatible with high-throughput data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/NCI-E-084-2019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Specialized Tissue Collection Device for the Preservation and Transportation of Needle Biopsies</title>
      <link>http://default/bundle/nci-e-128-2017</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ability to hold and transport tissue, especially needle biopsies in a pre-defined and controlled environment is critical for the preservation of biopsy samples in downstream analytic applications. Currently, tissue specimens are placed in open containers with variable, poorly controlled solutions applied to them, often in less than sterile conditions.  Evaluation of the tissue by examination through a stereoscope or similar approaches to determine adequacy is limited and requires manipulation of the tissue that can further damage the tissue. The entire process lacks standardization, which is in stark contrast to the handling of blood, that is collected and transported in well-defined containers that have individualized pre-analytic preservatives and downstream protocols. &lt;br /&gt;
	 &lt;br /&gt;
	Researchers at National Institutes of Health (NIH) have developed a tissue collection and storage container that allows for the direct deposition of tissue into the container while stabilizing the sample for transport in a specific solution and/or gas. This new device will primarily be used for needle biopsies to collect tissue samples and maintain their integrity for subsequent analysis. Additional features of the tissue storage container will include materials to physically stabilize and allow for direct examination of the sample by microscopy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This system is available for co-development or licensing to interested companies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/NCI-E-128-2017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic Bacterial Nanoparticles as Drug and Vaccine Delivery Vehicles</title>
      <link>http://default/bundle/nci-e-098-2015</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bacterial spores can be modified to display molecules of interest, including drugs, immunogenic peptides, antibodies and other functional proteins of interest (such as enzymes).  The resulting engineered bacterial spores can provide many useful functions such as the treatment of infections, use as an adjuvant for the delivery of vaccines, and the enzymatic degradation of environmental pollutants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the National Cancer Institute’s (NCI) &lt;a href="https://ccr.cancer.gov/Laboratory-of-Molecular-Biology" rel="nofollow"&gt;Laboratory of Molecular Biology&lt;/a&gt; have developed a novel, synthetic spore husk-encased lipid bilayer (SSHEL) particle that is uniquely suited for a variety of these functions. The assembly of SSHELs involves the insertion of the bacterial spore coat protein SpoVM into a lipid bilayer that is located on a synthetic core particle.  SpoVM serves as a structural element and recruitment factor for the bacterial spore coat protein SpoIVA.  When SpoIVA is conjugated to streptavidin, the SSHEL can bind to another molecule through a biotin linkage.  This leads to the creation of a specialized SSHEL that can serve a particular biological function.  The lab's pre-clinical work has demonstrated that SSHELs loaded with Doxorubicin reduced the tumor burden in a mouse tumor xenograft model of HER2-positive ovarian cancer.  By varying the ratio of streptavidin-conjugated and unconjugated SpoIVA protein used in the manufacture of the SSHEL, it is possible to tailor the amount of functional molecule that is present in the SSHEL.  This affords greater control over the level of activity that is provided by the SSHEL, thereby allowing the fine tuning of its function.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/NCI-E-098-2015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fluorescent Nanodiamonds as Fiducial Markers for Microscopy</title>
      <link>http://default/tech/tab-2998</link>
      <description>The invention relates to fluorescent nanodiamonds (FNDs) and their uses as fiducial markers for microscopy.  FNDs are bright fluorescent probes that do not blink or bleach and have broad fluorescence excitation and emission peaks.  The fluorescence intensity can be readily controlled by the size of the FND, the number of fluorescent centers produced in the nanodiamonds, or in situ through the application of a weak magnetic field.  The particular advantage of the FND compositions of this invention are that they are particularly useful for extended imaging of a single sample over time periods that can be as long as a week or more. In an exemplary embodiment, FNDs are immobilized in a substrate that are coated with an inert top coating, like silicon dioxide, or transparent polymer (e.g. poly-L-lysine, poly-L-arginine, or siloxanes).  Generally, any suitable methods known for surface functionalization of the substrate can be used to make the composition.  In another aspect of this invention, the inventors designed software for super-resolution imaging correction method is employed to precisely determine the position coordinates of each of a set of FNDs in a plurality of images by using Gaussian fitting of the point spread function comprises each of the FNDs in the plurality of images.  The calculated correction is then used to displace each image to align the coordinates of the FNDs.  The positions of the FNDs can be tracked with sub-nanometer precision and residual drift can be reduced to the nanometer scale over hundreds of hours of tracking.</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/TAB-2998</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
