<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:sioc="http://rdfs.org/sioc/ns#" xmlns:sioct="http://rdfs.org/sioc/types#" xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" version="2.0" xml:base="https://techtransfer.cancer.gov/rss/diagnostics/abstracts.xml">
  <channel>
    <title>Research Materials</title>
    <link>http://www.example.com</link>
    <description>Available Technologies from the Technology Transfer Center.</description>
    <language/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.example.com" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Method for Assembling Decellularized Tissue Extracellular Matrix in 3D Tumor Spheroids</title>
      <link>http://default/bundle/nci-e-127-2022</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cell culture investigations using spheroids and organoid models have had a major impact on biomedical advancement as alternative sources for costly, in vivo animal testing.  However, these 3-D cell constructs are limited in that they do not integrate extracellular components within the structure important for more reliable and accurate biological responses.  Extracellular matrix (ECM) from decellularized tissues provide a physical scaffolding and offers crucial biochemical and biomechanical cues for cellular constituents. Current spheroid and/or organoid 3D culture platforms only surround the cell structure with ECM, if ECM components are included at all. Therefore, these current models: (1) do not reflect the complexity of an in vivo micro-environment, (2) don’t provide signaling ligands for cells where they reside and (3) don’t provide standardizable models for 3D cell-based research. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current invention describes a novel method to create compact, self-contained spheroid integrating both cells and tissue ECM-dense regions within the spheroid – superior to traditional, cell-only spheroids. The method promotes integration with fibroblasts and macrophages after cells are assembled with decellularized tissue ECM. The results suggest incorporating decellularized tissue ECM within a spheroid offers an improved ex vivo tumor microenvironment influencing cancer phenotype in cell invasion and migration. The usage of decellularized tissue ECM in this technology offers a relatively standardizable, reproducible and valuable tool for drug discovery and diagnostic purposes. It provides accurate assessment of cell behavior and response to perturbation in an in vivo microenvironment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technology is available  licenseng and collaboration opportunities to interested entities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/NCI-E-127-2022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mice, Organs, and Mouse Alleles Carrying Germline and Conditional Deletions of the Zbtb7b Gene</title>
      <link>http://default/bundle/nci-e-226-2022</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Zbtb7b gene encodes the zinc finger transcription factor ThPOK (also known as cKrox) that promotes CD4 lineage differentiation in immature T cells. CD4+ T cells, also known as “helper” T cells, are critical for long-term immunity against pathogens as well as for promoting CD8+ “effector” T cell and effective B cell responses. ThPOK is needed for the development and functional fitness of CD4+ T cells as well as multiple aspects of the immune response to infection. As such, ThPOK offers a potential target for immune regulation. For example, increasing the activity of ThPOK may enhance the efficacy of immunization strategies against infections or cancer; diseases associated with CD4+ T cell deficiency. Alternatively, inhibitors of ThPOK could offer new ways to interfere with CD4+ T cell activity, offering therapeutic benefit in inflammatory or autoimmune diseases such as multiple sclerosis and rheumatoid arthritis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the National Cancer Institute (NCI) developed mouse alleles carrying germline and conditional deletions of the Zbtb7b gene. These alleles were used to generate mice which demonstrate the Zbtb7b gene is essential for CD4+ T cell development and function. These mice can be used to study the function of ThPOK and the role of CD4+ T cells in the immune system. In addition to generating mice that are homozygous for the Zbtb7b gene deletion, the researchers generated mice that can be beneficial as experimental controls. One such mouse line is heterozygous for the Zbtb7b gene deletion; it carries one wild-type allele and one knockout allele. The other mouse line appears wild-type phenotypically but contains a “floxed” version of the Zbtb7b gene flanked by LoxP sites. It may be used to generate additional conditional deletions for the temporal and spatial regulation of gene expression. Given the importance of CD4+ T cells for the immune system, these mice are applicable to preclinical studies regarding a wide variety of human disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NCI seeks parties interested in licensing this mouse model, including the mice, organs, tissues, and other derivatives from mice carrying deletions of the Zbtb7b gene. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/NCI-E-226-2022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Method for Blocking PSMA-targeted Radionuclide Therapies from Exocrine Organ Uptake</title>
      <link>http://default/tech/tab-3783</link>
      <description>This technology includes a method to block tissue-specific uptake of radionuclide therapies, thus reducing treatment side effects. Radionuclide therapies targeting prostate-specific membrane antigen (FOLH1) are promising for the treatment of prostate cancer. However, due to expression in secretory organs such as the salivary gland, these tissues are susceptible to damage from tissue-targeted ionizing radiation decay events significantly impacting the wide spread clinical use of these drugs. We have developed a simple method to block tissue-specific uptake locally using a retroductal approach and performed preliminary proof-of-concept studies to illustrate this effect. This is a major barrier to wide spread implementation of alpha-emitted conjugated DCFPyL (PSMA synthetic ligand, and all other catalytic site targeting synthetic ligands. Because of the expression pattern of PSMA in the exocrine organs (e.g., the apical membrane of acinar cells in the salivary gland), and the exquisite sensitivity of these organs to ionizing radiation, exposure to this alpha-emitted therapy results in severe and permanent dysfunction.</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/TAB-3783</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Oxygen-induced Expression Vector for Production of Recombinant Proteins in Escherichia Coli</title>
      <link>http://default/tech/tab-3748</link>
      <description>This technology includes a new method to induce recombinant protein expression in E. coli through the activating the SoxS promoter by molecular oxygen. We previously discovered that the SoxRS regulon of E. coli is activated in response to elevated dissolved oxygen concentration mainly to protect the bacteria from possible oxygen damage. We hypothesized that the 16-fold increase in the expression of this regulon make it possible candidate for inducing the expression of recombinant proteins. Compared with the existing induction approaches oxygen induction offers several advantages; it does not involve addition or depletion of growth factors or nutrients, addition of chemical inducers or temperature changes that can affect growth and metabolism of the producing bacteria. It also offers another advantage by not affecting the composition of the growth media simplifying the recovery and purification process.</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/TAB-3748</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cell Lines that Constitutively Express High-Frequency KRAS and P53 Mutations and Human Leukocyte Antigens (HLAs)</title>
      <link>http://default/bundle/nci-e-182-2022</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Adoptive cell therapy (ACT) is a breakthrough form of cancer immunotherapy that utilizes tumor infiltrating lymphocytes (TILs) or genetically engineered T cells to attack tumor cells through recognition of tumor-specific antigens. A major hurdle in the development of ACT is the identification and isolation of T cells that recognize antigens that are expressed by tumor cells but not by healthy tissues. Current methods to identify such T cells involve extracting autologous antigen presenting cells (APCs) from patients in an expensive, laborious, and time-consuming process. In addition, the quantity and quality of extracted APCs varies significantly between patients, necessitating a novel, standardized approach.&lt;br /&gt;
	Researchers at the National Cancer Institute (NCI) developed a library of cell lines to identify T cells that specifically target tumor cells, thus eliminating the need for autologous APCs. These cell lines stably express tumor-specific antigens at a high level in the tandem minigene (TMG) format. The antigens expressed arise from mutations in the RAS or p53 genes. These mutations are also referred to as “hotspot” driver mutations because they are shared among many cancer patients and are the most commonly mutated genes in solid tumors. The cells also stably and highly express Class-I or Class-II human leukocyte antigens (HLAs) of interest, allowing for determination of HLA restriction. These cell lines offer a versatile, quick, and cost-effective method to identify, isolate, and expand tumor-reactive T cells.&lt;br /&gt;
	The NCI seeks parties interested in licensing this library of cell lines stably expressing tumor-specific antigens and HLAs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/NCI-E-182-2022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monoclonal Antibodies for the Recognition of Oncogene Fusions and Alveolar Rhabdomyosarcoma (ARMS) Diagnosis</title>
      <link>http://default/tech/tab-3639</link>
      <description>This technology includes monoclonal antibody (mAb) that binds to the junction region of the PAX3-FOXO1 and PAX7-FOXO1 fusion protein for the diagnosis of Alveolar Rhabdomyosarcoma (ARMS). Specifically, two monoclonal antibodies (PFM.1 and PFM.2) have been isolated that recognize the 92kDa bands found uniquely to the pediatric striated muscle tumors of the type Alveolar Rhabdomyosarcoma (ARMS) carrying the characteristic t(2;13)(q35;q14) or t(1;13)(p36;q14) chromosomal translocations. This in-frame fusion protein is unique to the most common type of ARMS and acts as a potent transcriptional activator as the result of a decreased regulatory (of PAX3/7) sensitivity of the C-terminal domain of FOXO1. The mAbs recognize the ARMS fusion protein PAX3/7 FKHR on western analysis and do not recognize PAX3/7 or FOXO1 alone. The antibodies work by Westerns, Co-Immunoprecipitation, Chromatin Immunoprecipitation Sequencing (CHipSeq), and immunohistochemistry.</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/TAB-3639</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formulation of a Modified Stable FGF-1 (TTHX1114) to Accelerate Corneal Endothelium Regeneration</title>
      <link>http://default/tech/tab-3584</link>
      <description>This technology includes the use of a novel formulation for an engineered version of Fibroblast Growth Factor 1 (FGF1), TTHX1114, that can be used to accelerate regeneration of the corneal endothelium after surgical lesions. FGFs are well-established regulators of migration and proliferation of corneal endothelial cells (CECs).</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/TAB-3584</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Treatment of primary hyperoxalurias with small molecule lactate dehydrogenase inhibitors such as WO2018005807A1</title>
      <link>http://default/tech/tab-3582</link>
      <description>This technology includes the use of novel lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) inhibitors, including WO2018005807A1, for the treatment of primary hyperoxalurias (PHs). PHs are rare autosomal recessive disorders caused by overproduction of oxalate, leading to recurrent calcium oxalate kidney stone disease, and in some cases end-stage renal disease. One potential strategy to treat PHs is to reduce the production of oxalate by diminishing the activity of LDH, the proposed key enzyme responsible for converting glyoxylate to oxalate. Biochemical and cell-based assays were used to identify and characterize novel potent inhibitors of LDH that prevent the conversion of glyoxylate to oxalate.</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/TAB-3582</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimized Nucleotide Sequence for RLIP-76 - A Membrane-associated Lipid Peroxidation Transporter for Radiation Poisoning</title>
      <link>http://default/tech/tab-3571</link>
      <description>This technology includes a codon optimized expression vector for the high expression and production of RLIP-76 which can be used to provide protection from radiation. RLIP-76 is a multifunctional membrane protein that transports glutathione conjugates of electrophilic compounds outside the cell. The sequence was generated with codon bias alterations, reduction of secondary structure, lowering of GC content, and removal of cryptic elements that could affect expression in E.coli. The final plasmid construct was flanked by Nde1 and Xho1 restriction sites, and contained a triple stop codon to ensure complete translation stop without readthrough.</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/TAB-3571</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potency Assay for Membrane Transporter Protein-based Drugs Acting on Antioxidant, Redox, and Apoptosis Response Pathways</title>
      <link>http://default/tech/tab-3568</link>
      <description>This technology includes a method of analyzing the potency of membrane transporter protein-based drugs acting on intracellular antioxidant and redox response pathways (and associated apoptosis pathways), wherein the drug delivery and activity is lipid associated. The present invention is a cell-based bioassay for measuring the bioactivity of drug substance and formulated drug product by determining the drug's dose-dependent inhibitory effects on 4 hydroxynonenal (4-HNE)-induced antioxidant response element (ARE) activity. The present invention covers use of HEK293 ARE-Luc Stable cell line as the detection system, high-throughput 96-well format, drug dilution approach, enclosure of negative controls with non-relevant heterologous proteins, use of the stimulator 4-HNE, and the optimal measurement time points with the ARE luciferase reporter gene. This is also an effective method to make liposome-drug substance mixtures for assembly of drug substance proteins into cellular membranes by using premade empty liposomes as a drug delivery system.</description>
      <pubDate/>
      <dc:creator>Anonymous</dc:creator>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.example.com/TAB-3568</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
